Tim Westberg

Lake Elsinore, CA, 92532 **Phone**: (951) 852-2584

Email: <u>TimWestberg@formulagen.com</u> GitHub: <u>https://github.com/Timwestberg</u>

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/tim-westberg/

Portfolio: https://timwestberg.com

I am a user-focused Web Developer with a passion for integrating technologies to solve problems and improve existing methods. My background in office management, bookkeeping, and sales provides me with a unique perspective on how end-users interact with websites and software platforms. I enjoy approaching programming challenges from different angles and collaborating with others to create meaningful web applications that effectively elevate the user and client experience. My ultimate goal is to provide solutions that are simple and intuitive to clients.

Projects

Schedulize (2019) (Full stack; MERN stack)

Scheduling Application

React application built for scheduling contractors to appointments on an agency level.
Organizes data for agencies to efficiently locate, create, and update new work orders.

Development

- Led team of two developers
- Maintained constant communication with client
- Three months to complete, but I continue to maintain, update, and improve the application based on user needs

Front End

- ReactJS
- Material Design Bootstrap (MDB)
- NodeJS

Back End

- MongoDB
- ExpressJS

Gig It (October 2019) (Fullstack; JAM Stack)

Information Application

- React application that provides musicians with a platform to share news, updates, and shows.
- Two developers
- One month, but currently rebuilding using ReactJS, Redux, and Firebase

Front End

- ReactJS
- MDBootstrap

Back End

- Firebase Realtime Database
- Firebase Authentication

Axios

- Google Maps API
- Google Geocoding

- NodeJS
 - Redux

Happy Camper (2018) (JavaScript)

Information Application

• National park database with reviews to help with travel and camping needs.

Development

- Four developers
- One month to complete

Front End

- iQuery
- Custom design & CSS
- NodeJS

- Axios
- National Parks API

Work Experience

Oscar Campana (O.C.) Interpreting Agency Carlsbad, CA

May 2017 – Present

Application Developer and Technology Lead

- Select & manage office technologies (e.g., computers, web applications, phone systems)
- Provide technology training to all employees
- Designed custom web application for scheduling appointments and organizing client data ("Schedulize"; see above)

Administrative Assistant

- Manage company emails and employee training
- Process confidential client information
- QuickBooks manager

Bill Cary CPA, CA

March 2012 – 2014; Jan 2016 – June 2017

Administrative Assistant

- Designed and managed a comprehensive filing system
- Bookkeeping
- Data entry (e.g., tax records)
- Handled all outgoing mail

National Agents Alliance, Rancho Cucamonga, CA

August 2014 – December 2016

Life Insurance Agent and Hiring Assistant Manager

- Interviewed and hired potential job candidates.
- Excelled at sales and provided excellent customer service
- Gained interpersonal experience and extensive leadership training
- Worked in a team-oriented environment

T.West Financial, Lake Elsinore, CA

Jan 2010 – December 2016

Bookkeeper

- Entered transactions using QuickBooks
- Class tracking
- Bank reconciliation
- Invoicing

Education

Computer Science, Bachelor of Science (B.S.) in Progress Mira Costa Community College, Carlsbad, California August 2017 – Present

Full Stack Development and MERN Stack Certification University of California San Diego August 2018 – January 2019

I have experience with:

- React.js
- Redux.js
- React-redux
- React-Thunk
- Express
- Node.js
- Mongoose
- MongoDB
- MySQL
- Material Design
- Material CSS
- Axios

- Microsoft Word, Excel, PowerPoint
- Outlook
- Networking, Computer IT
- Passport.js
- JavaScript,
- JQUERY
- Node.js,
- HTML
- CSS
- Quick Books Enterprise and lower, Quick Books Point of Sale
- Typing: 75 words per minute